A Jedi shall not know anger. Nor hatred. Nor love.
Star Wars: Episode II - Attack of the Clones is a adventure,
action, science fiction film directed by George Lucas.
Following an assassination attempt on Senator Padmé Amidala, Jedi Knights Anakin Skywalker and Obi-Wan Kenobi
investigate a mysterious plot into the heart of the Separatist movement and the beginning of the Clone Wars.
Anakin Skywalker, played by Hayden Christensen.
Obi-Wan Kenobi, played by Ewan McGregor.
Padmé Amidala, played by Natalie Portman.
Count Dooku, played by Christopher Lee.
Mace Windu, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Yoda (voice), played by Frank Oz.
Star Wars: Attack of the Clones (also known as Star Wars: Episode II – Attack of the Clones) is a 2002 American
epic space opera film directed by George Lucas from a screenplay he co-wrote with Jonathan Hales.
The sequel to The Phantom Menace (1999), it is the fifth entry in the Star Wars
film series and second chronological chapter of the "Skywalker Saga".
The film stars Ewan McGregor, Natalie Portman, Hayden
Christensen, Ian McDiarmid, Samuel L.
Jackson, Christopher Lee, Anthony Daniels, Kenny Baker, and Frank Oz.
The story is set ten years after The Phantom Menace, as thousands of planetary systems slowly secede from the Galactic
Republic and join the newly formed Confederacy of Independent Systems, led by former Jedi Master Count Dooku.
With the galaxy on the brink of civil war, Obi-Wan Kenobi investigates a mysterious assassination attempt on Senator Padmé Amidala,
which leads him to uncover a clone army in service of the Republic and the truth behind the Separatist movement.
Meanwhile, his apprentice Anakin Skywalker is assigned to protect
Amidala and develops a secret romance with her.
Soon, the trio witness the onset of a new threat to the galaxy: the Clone Wars.
Development of Attack of the Clones began in March 2000, some
months after the release of The Phantom Menace.
By June 2000, Lucas and Hales completed a draft of the script, and
principal photography took place from June to September 2000.
The film crew primarily shot at Fox Studios Australia in Sydney, with
additional footage filmed in Tunisia, Italy and Spain.
It was one of the first motion pictures shot completely on
a high-definition digital 24-frame system.
Attack of the Clones was released by 20th Century Fox
in the United States on May 16, 2002.
It received mixed reviews from critics; the film's increased focus on action was
praised, while the characters and dialogue were regarded more critically.
It performed well at the box office, making $653.8 million worldwide.
Yet, it became the first Star Wars film to get outgrossed in its year of
release, becoming the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2002 worldwide.
Revenge of the Sith (2005) followed Attack of the Clones,
concluding the Star Wars prequel trilogy.
The film explores themes of army, laser gun, senate, investigation, sequel.
The tone is thought_provoking.